<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home – Policies</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiopreview/policy/</link><description>Recent content in Policies on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Bank for International Settlements. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiopreview/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiopreview/policy/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiopreview/policy/privacy/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="draft">DRAFT&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this Privacy Policy, &amp;ldquo;sdmx.io Website&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Site&amp;rdquo; means this website &lt;a href="https://sdmx.io" title="https://sdmx.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://sdmx.io&lt;/a>
and &amp;ldquo;Users&amp;rdquo; means its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>sdmx.io recognises your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your information is used and shared online. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits the sdmx.io Website and will only collect and use information in ways that are useful to you and in a manner consistent with your rights and our obligations under the law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Policy applies to our use of any and all information collected by us in relation to your use of the sdmx.io Website. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance of our Privacy Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of the sdmx.io Website. If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using the sdmx.io Website immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of the sdmx.io Website. It does not extend to any websites that are linked to from the sdmx.io Website (whether we provide those links or whether they are shared by other Users). We have no control over how your information is collected, stored or used by other websites and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any information to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="information-collected">Information collected&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We will collect information from Users when it is voluntarily submitted such as when signing-up to receive email alerts. The sdmx.io Website may also automatically collect information like Users&amp;rsquo; browsing hostory as well as certain other information relating to Users&amp;rsquo; use of and visits to the Site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We may collect some or all of the following information:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organisation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Job title / profession&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IP address&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Browser type&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We use the HTTPS protocol to authenticate Our Site and ensure privacy by encrypting communications between your browser and the Site&amp;rsquo;s servers. You can verify that the connection is secure by looking for the ‘padlock’ symbol displayed by most browsers in the address bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="use-of-information-collected">Use of information collected&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We may use the information we collect from you the extent necessary for delivering our services to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information that personally identifies Users (&amp;ldquo;Personally Identifiable Information&amp;rdquo;) including user&amp;rsquo;s name and email address may be used for the purpose of sending email communications and personalising and improving the sdmx.io Website and services. Such Personally Identifable Information will be treated as confidential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may unsubscribe from email communications at any time by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>using the &lt;a href="../../comms/unsubscribe" title="Unsubscribe">Unsubscribe&lt;/a>
; or&lt;/li>
&lt;li>emailing us at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@sdmx.io" title="contact@sdmx.io">contact@sdmx.io&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We use a third-party provider, MailChimp, to deliver our emails. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our email communications. For more information, please see &lt;a href="https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/" title="MailChimp’s Privacy Policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MailChimp’s Privacy Policy&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>